Drawn by a landscape as white as snow,
真っ白な景色にいま誘われて
Masshiro na keshiki ni ima sasowarete
I'm headed toward an unseen world.
僕は行くよ　まだ見ぬ世界へ
Boku wa yuku yo mada minu sekai e
I've been traveling while lost
迷子のまま旅していた
Maigo no mama tabi shiteita
Under this gray sky.
鼠色の空の下
Nezumiiro no sora no shita
Every day with new maps, stained with my many dreams.
日替わりの地図 いくつもの夢が滲んでいた
Higawari no chizu ikutsumo no yume ga nijindeita
I wonder if someday,
いつかはさ
Itsuka wa sa
Even with these tiny steps of mine,
ちっぽけな僕のこの歩幅でも
Chippoke na boku no kono hohaba demo
I'll be able to travel beyond those clouds.
あの雲の向こうまで行けるかな
Ano kumo no mukou made yukeru kana
I put on a bold front.
強がって
Tsuyogatte
End up hurting myself.
キズついた
Kizutsuita
I feel empty inside.
心透かしたように
Kokoro sukashita youni
It's started to rain,
降り出した
Furidashita
And the raindrops
雨粒たちが
Amatsubu tachi ga
Began to repeat their scattered reflections.
乱反射繰り返す
Ranhansha kurikaesu
These straight rays of light
真っ直ぐな光が
Massugu na hikari ga
Start to cross one another.
交差して
Kousa shite
And without telling anyone where they're headed,
行き先も告げぬまま
Yakusaki mo tsugenumama
Across the endless distances,
どこまでも
Doko made mo
They pass through all matter.
突き抜ける
Tsukinukeru
I burn these faint afterimages onto my eyes.
淡い残像　両目に焼きつけて
Awai zanzou ryoume ni yakitsukete
Under this sky,
この空の下
Kono sora no shita
Wherever I am,
どんなとこにいても
Donna toko ni itemo
I should be able to reach
届くはずなんだ
Todoku hazu nanda
The unseen world.
まだ見ぬ世界へ
Mada minu sekai e
Ed!
エド
You little shit!
くそが
Lin!
リン
You bastard!
野郎
Kill... me...
殺して
Save me...
助けて
Please... kill me!
お願い　殺して
Please...
お願い
I want to die...
お母さん
Mommy!
What are you just staring out into space for, idiot?!
ボサっとするな　バカ野郎
Why are you hesitating?!
何を躊躇っている
There are...
人が
There are people inside of him...
中に人がいた
They want our help.
助けを求めてる
No! They're monsters!
違う　化け物だ
But...
でも
Pull yourself together!
割り切れ　あれは化け物だ
They're monsters!
殺せ
Kill me!
Mommy!
ママ
Please! Give me back my child!
子供を返して
Shut up! Stop it!
うるさい　やめろ
Dad!
父さん
It hurts...
苦しい
死にたい…  助けて…
Help me!
I said, "Stop it!"
やめろって
Ed.
おにいちゃん
Let's play.
遊ぼう
遊ぼうよ
遊びは終わりだ
Playtime's over.
Damn...
ちく…しょう
...it...
助けて
Help me...
You don't understand the pain...
分かるまい　この苦しみ
Ed! Wake up!
エド　起きろ
Come to your senses!
目を覚ませ
Join us!
Ed!
エド
Good! Good!
オーライ　オーライ
All right, bring it over this way!
よし　こっちだ
Oh yeah.
ああ　こいつ
I saw it over by the waste plant earlier.
さっきあっちの廃工場辺りで見かけたよ
If I recall, it was with some huge guy in an armor.
なんかでかい鎧が連れて歩いてたなぁ
Armor?
鎧
はっ　もしや昨日の
Don't tell me it's the one from yesterday!
I'll never forgive him for kidnapping Shao May!
許せません　あの鎧
シャオメイをさらうなんて
Demon! Devil! Loincloth!
鬼　悪魔　ふんどし
There she is! Shao Ma-
いた　シャオメ
Wait.
待て
That fat one...
あの太いヤツ　確か人造人間と呼ばれていた
If I recall, they called him a Homunculus.
Homunculus?
人造人間
Their regeneration ability matches that of an immortal.
不死身に近い再生力を持っている
We can't jump in carelessly.
迂闊に手出しはできん
Immortal?
不死身　願ってもない
This is my chance! Let's go after him!
追いかけましょう
I told you. He's not an easy opponent.
言っただろ　簡単にいく相手ではないぞ
Why are those two together?
なぜあの二人が一緒に
What's wrong?
どうした
This place... is strange.
ここ　変です
I've had a feeling that something was out of place, ever since I arrived in this country, but...
この国に入ってからずっと違和感があったのですが
This is...
これは
There are things crawling beneath my feet... and a lot of them...
足の下を沢山の何かが　はいずり回っている
What's wrong? Are you cold?
どうしたの　寒い
You okay?
大丈夫
This way.
こっち
I never would've thought something like this was under Central...
セントラルの地下にこんなとこが
W-What the heck is this?!
なっ　なんだよこれ
That was done by the gatekeepers.
門番の仕業だよ
Gatekeepers?
門番
They won't attack you if you're with me.
おでといれば殺されないよ
There's something up there.
何かいる
Do we still have a long way to go?
まだまだ先
A long way.
まだまだ先だよ
We're meeting your father, right?
お父様だっけ
He knows where people go after you swallow them, right?
飲まれた人たちの行き先を知ってるよね
Father knows everything.
お父様なんでも知ってる
Brother... You're alive, right?
兄さん　生きてるよね
Brother...
兄さん
What's that?
なんだ
A red... stone?
赤い　石
Right, Envy's core.
そっか　エンヴィーの核
賢者の石だ
A philosopher's stone.
After all the time we spent looking for one,
there's one right in front of me...
あれだけ探したのに
こんなところにあるなんて
Let me out, Envy!
出せ　エンヴィー
It stinks in here!
臭ぇんだよ
What?
We may be able to get out of here!
ここから出られるかもしれねぇ
Let's work together, Envy!
協力しろ　エンヴィー
What in the world are these?
これは一体
They are chimera.
合成獣というやつだ
There's no end to them.
キリがないな
No...
イヤだ
As I thought... there's something beneath us...
やっぱり　下に何かいます
Are they chimera?
合成獣か
No.
違います
Is this... a person?!
これは　人
Father made us all!
お父様にみんなつくってもらった
Me, Lust, and Envy!
おでもラストもエンヴィーも
It's loud up there.
何やら騒々しい
Someone's coming...
誰か来るな
私は親の名も顔も
I don't remember my parents' names, their faces, or even my own name.
自身の名前すら覚えていない
No... I don't remember if I was abandoned or sold before I had even been given a name.
いや　名を付けられる前に捨てられたか売られたか
Which one of you will lead this country?
この国を背負って立つのは誰かな
Will it be you?
君かな
「大総統候補」
We were called the "Führer President Candidates".
我々はそう呼ばれた
そして１か所に集められ　さまざまな教育を受けた
And we were all gathered into one place and educated in many different fields.
帝王学　人間学から
How to be a good emperor, anthropology...
We were trained in military combat, marksmanship, and swordsmanship until we were highly capable.
軍隊格闘　射撃　剣術に至るまで
気にするな
Don't sweat it.
彼は君が目的を遂げるための駒だったんだ
He was just a pawn for you to achieve your goal.
自分がこの国を動かす人物になる
"I will lead this country someday."
そう信じ私はどんな訓練にも耐えた
With that thought in mind,
I endured the toughest of trainings.
He was no good either.
この者もダメでした
Next.
次だ
そこに横になって
Lie down here.
あの　これは
Umm... What is this about?
Relax.
楽にしていたまえ
すぐに終わる
It'll be over soon.
何をする気ですか
What are you planning to do?! Those bodies are...
あの死体は
１２人目か
This is the twelfth one, huh?
Are you the one...
我が憤怒を受け入れるのは
...who will receive my wrath?
君か
A philosopher's stone is a high energy substance that includes the souls of many humans.
賢者の石は多くの人間の魂が含まれた高エネルギー体だ
As it enters a human's body, it goes on a rampage and tries to take over.
人間の体へ入ると拒絶反応で暴れ回り
肉体を乗っ取ろうとする
The destruction and reconstruction by the stone is repeated until either the body dies or wins.
石による破壊と補修は
元の体が死ぬか
賢者の石に打ち勝つまで繰り返された
やがて
Eventually...
Amazing!
すばらしい
A new species of life!
新たな人類だ
Congratulations.
おめでとう
You've been selected to be the man who will lead this country.
君はこの国を導くリーダーとして選ばれたのだ
He will prepare everything you may need.
あのお方が必要なすべてを用意してくださる
君の名は今日から
From this day on, your name shall be...
キング·ブラッドレイ
King Bradley!
残ったのはたった一つの魂と憤怒の感情のみ
All that was left was a soul and the emotion of wrath.
I don't even know if this soul belongs to someone who was turned into the stone, or if it was mine to begin with.
この魂が賢者の石にされた誰かのものなのか
もともとの己のものなのか
もう　分からんのだ
元は人間だというのなら
If you were human, couldn't you live as a human instead of a Homunculus, sir?
人造人間としてではなく
人間として生きることはできないのですか 閣下
人間に戻れと
You're telling me to go back to being a human?
That's impossible.
無理だな
This body has far surpassed human capabilities.
この体は人間を超越した
It's far superior.
遥かに優れた品種だ
君たち人間が人間であることに誇りを持っているように
Just as how you humans are proud to be human,
we are proud to be Homunculi.
我々にも人造人間としてのプライドがある
I'm sure that woman took that pride to her death, as well.
あの女も　そのプライドを持って死んでいっただろう
痛っ
Ow.
Just something temporary.
応急処置だ
Thanks.
ありがと
この辺にあるのは全部集めたよ
I've collected all the ones around here.
これ　みんなクセルクセスの
Are these all from Xerxes?
Yeah.
ああ　遺跡の神殿にあった大壁画の一部だ
It's a portion of the mural that was in a temple in the ruins.
初めてあの壁画を見た時
When I first saw it,
I thought it was a transmutation circle for a philosopher's stone, like the one beneath Research Laboratory 5.
第五研究所地下にあったのと同じ
賢者の石の錬成陣かと思った
But I was wrong.
だが違う
The sun represents the soul.
太陽は魂　月は精神を表す
The moon represents the mind.
そして壁画の描かれた石
And this stone which has the mural on it. This represents the body.
これは肉体を表す
Come on... explain it so I can understand.
おいおい　分かりやすく説明してくれよ
Basically, what was drawn there...
つまり　あそこに描かれていたのは
...is a circle for human transmutation.
人体錬成の陣だ
Human transmutation?
人体錬成
ってことは　死者をよみがえらせるための
So that means, to raise the dead...
No.
いや　錬金術の原則は等価交換だ
The principle of alchemy is equivalent exchange.
One cannot create a soul that doesn't exist in this world, at least through alchemy.
この世に存在しない魂を錬成によって
生み出すことはできない
I've confirmed that.
そのことは確かめた
で　ここを出る方法を閃いたんだが
So, I've thought of a way to get out of here.
What if I transmute myself from scratch...
生きている人間を
オレがオレを錬成し直すってのはどうだ
A human that's alive?
Transmute from scratch?
錬成し直す
ああ
Yeah.
I use this transmutation circle to decompose myself, then put myself back together.
オレがこの錬成陣を使って自分を分解し
また元どおりに再構築する
That's also human transmutation.
これも人体錬成だ　きっと扉が開く
The gate should open.
グラトニーが偽りの真理の扉だというなら
If Gluttony is a fake Gate of Truth,
shouldn't we be able to get to
the real world by going through the real gate?
正しい扉をくぐれば
正しい空間に出られるんじゃないだろうか
オレが扉を開け
I'll open the gate; you guys leap in.
お前らはそこに飛び込む
What if this doesn't work?
失敗したらどうなる
リバウンドだ
Then we suffer from rebound.
All of the effects of the rebound go to the one who attempted it.
術の失敗は行使した者にすべて跳ね返る
In this case, me.
この場合はオレにな
オレは錬金術に関しては門外漢だ
I know nothing about alchemy.
任せよう
I'll leave it to you.
All right.
よし
So, Envy, there's something I need to ask you.
で　エンヴィー
てめぇに聞いておきたいことがある
オレが見たクセルクセスの大壁画
The mural I saw at Xerxes looked like this.
ざっとこんな感じだ
気になるのはこの記号
I'm curious about this symbol.
It's the word representing God, but flipped over.
神を表す文字を上下ひっくり返したもの
And the dragon with two heads.
そして　２頭の竜
これは完全なる存在を示す
This represents the perfect being.
つまり　神を地に落とし
This means "I will cast God from the Heavens to the Earth, and become the perfect being."
自らが完全な存在となるって意味だ
People think of outrageous things.
大それたことを考えるものだな
It would be wonderful if they had only thought about it.
考えただけならいい
問題は
The problem here is...
...this part, which is broken off.
欠けていたこの部分だ
A lion that swallows the sun.
太陽をのみ込む獅子の図
This represents the philosopher's stone.
これは賢者の石を示す
賢者の石の材料は生きた人間
And the ingredients of philosopher's stones are live humans.
そうだな　エンヴィー
Right, Envy?
ああ　そうだよ
Yeah, you're right.
Why did the nation of Xerxes,
a nation so prosperous, perish overnight?
あれほど栄えたクセルクセスの国が
一夜にしてなぜ滅んだ
Where did its citizens go?
国民の行方は
Isn't a portion of the ruins in here to cover up the evidence?
ここに遺跡の一部があるのは
証拠隠滅のためじゃないのか
お前ら　クセルクセス国民全員
You guys turned all of Xerxes' citizens into a philosopher's stone, didn't you?!
賢者の石にしちまったな
Who did it?!
誰がやった
Who transmuted themselves?!
自身を錬成したのは誰だ
国民全員を賢者の石にして
Who's the one who turned all of the country's people into a philosopher's stone for tremendous power...
その強大な力を手に入れ
...for the sole purpose of becoming a being that would surpass God?!
神をも超える存在になろうとしたのは誰だ
お前の言うお父様か
Is it the "Father" that you talked about?
Isn't that guy trying to recreate that event in this country by using you guys, the Homunculi?!
そいつは　お前ら人造人間を使って
この国でクセルクセス滅亡の
再現をやろうとしてるんじゃないのか
I'll tell you if you get us out of here.
ここから出られたら教えてやるよ
回りくどい話はやめようよ　鋼の錬金術師
Let's stop beating around the bush, Fullmetal Alchemist.
You need a toll if you're going to open the gate, right?
扉を開けるとなれば　必要なのは通行料だろ
Use it.
使えよ
Help me!
助けて　殺してくれ
Please, just kill me!
これ　みんなクセルクセスの人たちなんだな
These are all people from Xerxes, aren't they?
Their bodies and minds have rotted away in the ancient past, and they are beings who are solely used as an energy source.
肉体も精神も　とうの昔に朽ち果てて
エネルギーとして消費されるだけの存在さ
They don't even remember what they used to look like.
自分がどんな姿だったかも覚えちゃいないよ
Are you sympathizing with them?
同情か　くだらん感情だなぁ
What a stupid emotion.
The sole reason you want to think of them as humans is that you want to believe that your brother, who's only a soul, is human, too.
魂だけの弟を人間と認めたいから
似たようなこいつらを人間と思いたいだけだ
大昔に滅んだ木がかわいそうだからって
You hesitate to set fire to coal because you feel sorry for a tree that died ages ago?
石炭を火にくべるのを躊躇うのか
They can't return to being human anymore.
こいつらはもう人間には戻れない
Lay down a definition for a human with logic and not emotion, alchemist.
感情じゃなくて理屈で人間の定義に線を引けよ
錬金術師
よし
All right.
リン
Lin, if something happens to me,
tell everyone about what these guys are up to.
オレにもしものことがあったら
この連中の企みを外のヤツらに伝えてくれ
アメストリスがどうなろうと
Whatever happens to Amestris isn't my problem.
オレの知ったことじゃない
Hey!
お前な
There are people precious to you waiting for you in that country, right?
お前を待ってる大事な人たちがいる国だろ
生きてここから出て　自分で伝えろよ
Get out of here alive and tell them yourself.
I'm sorry. Please let me use your souls.
すみません　使わせてもらいます
Let's do this!
いくぞ
I thought that pose of putting their hands together looked similar to something...
あの手を合わせるポーズ
何かに似てると思ったら
It's almost like a prayer to God.
まるで神への祈りじゃないか
It's been a while since I've done this.
久しぶりだな
I never thought I'd open it again... under this situation.
こんなかたちでまた開けることになるなんて
Lin! Jump in!
リン　飛び込め
信用してるぞ　錬金術師
I'm counting on you, alchemist!
グラトニーに飲まれたときと同じ
This is the same sensation I felt while being swallowed by Gluttony...
Thank you...
ありがとう
The body and the soul are connected by the mind.
肉体と魂は精神によって繋がっている
オレの肉体の一部は真理の扉の前にある
A part of my body is before the Gate of Truth.
If I just let my mind guide me,
I should be able to get to the gate...
精神の導くまま　すべてを委ねて
扉へ
Oh, so you didn't come here to get your body back?
へえ　体を取り戻しに来たんじゃないのか
この中に　お父様がいるんだね
Your father is through here, right?
Yeah.
いるよ
ここに　兄さんの手がかりが
I can find clues on how to find my brother...
All right, I'm here.
よし　来たぞ
Why are there two gates?
なんで　扉が２つあるんだ
Al!
アル
アル　来い
Al! Come here!
Hurry up! Al!!!
早く来い　アル
アル
Al!!!
I can't.
ダメだよ
You're not my soul.
君は僕の魂じゃない
一緒に行けない
I can't go with you.
アルフォンス
Alphonse!
いつか　必ず迎えに来るぞ
Someday, I'll come and bring you back.
Wait for me.
待ってろ
Wait for me!!!
待ってろっ
Let it all out, Let it all out
I don't have to act tough, right?
強がらなくていいんだね
Tsuyogaranakute iindane
The scribbling someone made...
誰かが描いてった
Dareka ga kaitetta
On the wall, of a flower is swaying.
壁の落書きの花が　揺れる
Kabe no rakugaki no hana ga yureru
No one knows their true selves.
自分らしさなんて, 誰もわからないよ
Jibunrashisa nante dermo wakaranaiyo
Even though we both lose and gain
長い長い道の途中で
Nagai nagai michi no tochuu de
By embarking on this long, long path,
失くしたり, 拾ったり,
Nakushitari hirottari
And though there may be days loneliness strikes and makes us weep...
急に寂しくなって, 泣いちゃう日もあるけど
Kyuu ni samishikunatte naichau hi mo arukedo
Let's transform our tears and pains to stars.
涙も　痛みも　星に変えよう
Namida mo itami mo hoshi ni kaeyou
Let's light a candle to illuminate our tomorrow.
明日を照らす　灯りをともそう
Ashita wo terasu akari wo tomosou
And we'll hold our small hands over the fire to create stardust,
小さな手かざして　ふたりで作ろう
Chiisana te kazashite futari de tsukurou
And an eternity that shines so brilliantly.
星屑を　強く光る永遠を探そう
Hoshikuzu wo tsuyoku hikaru eien wo
Farewells may be unavoidable,
さよなら　いつかは来るかもしれない
Sayonara itsuka wa kurukamoshirenai
Yet the seasons continue to change obliviously.
季節はそれでも巡り巡ってく
Kisetsu wa soredemo meguri megutteku
Even if I lose myself, I'll continue to walk...
小さく迷っても　歩いてく
Chiisaku mayottemo aruiteku
Walk by your side.
君と歩いてく
Kimi to aruiteku
That's the only thing I'd like to never change.
それだけは変わらないでいようね
Sore dake wa kawaranaideiyoune
日本語字幕仕上げ：FAYFAY
幻影は炎の揺らめきに似て
It is hard to find the shape of an illusion, like a wavering flame.
その形をとらえることは難しい
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
そして炎は　時として残酷であり
And a flame can be cruel at times, but can also be a flame of hope.
また　希望である
次回　鋼の錬金術師
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
FULLMETAL ALCHEMIST
Episode 27, Interlude Party.
第二十七話　狭間の宴
自らの中にある闇を恐れてはいけない
You mustn't be afraid of the darkness inside of you.